hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so continuing with our topic on
test automation obstacles let's look at
our next obstacle which is called math
and as the name suggest uh we need to
perform math operation here okay so in
order to complete this obstacle we need
to complete the operation listed below
and we need to enter the result in the
result box okay so this might seem uh
pretty simple in the first instance but
the challenge here is um everything is
randomized okay so the two uh random
numbers you can see here are randomly
generated plus the upper end here which
is this minus sign this is also randomly
changing okay so if I refresh this page
now you will see that uh the numbers are
changing and sometimes the operant is
also changing so it could be a
multiplication it could be addition
subtraction or uh even a modular
operation okay so whatever the operation
you need to be able to uh handle that
into your automation okay so everything
uh should be parameterized here uh in a
way and using some conditions you need
to uh handle these changing random
numbers and operants okay so once we
enter uh the result here like for
instance here the result is 80 uh this
operation will be completed
okay now the ideal way of doing this um
would be in any programming language or
any automation tool you can make use of
uh the switch case right so if I talk
about Java you can make use of the
switch case where you can have different
uh case and based on that case you can
have a specific calculation right so it
will fit for this particular kind of
problem but uh tosa doesn't have a
switch case okay so we need to fall back
upon um the conditional statements and
we need to use the if condition in this
particular scenario okay so let's see
how we can do this in
tosa so coming back here uh I'm going to
go back to my modules uh section and
here we'll go to
obstacles here we will add another
module okay and then here uh we need to
have the numbers the randomly generated
numbers the uh operation okay and then
uh we need to have the result okay so
these are the four elements which we
have to add here so I'm going to save it
and close it now I'm going to copy the
obstacle number here and
then we are going to rename
this okay and then uh going back to test
cases we will add a new test case here
now
okay and then uh we are going to add the
module right
here
okay right um so the first step here is
to basically buffer all the values okay
so what we are going to do is we are
also going to uh name these module
attributes because these are randomly
changing so it won't remain the same
always right so we'll change the names
here and we'll call it
operand okay and now coming back to our
test case so now these are properly
displayed here so what I'm going to do
is I will be uh buffering all these
values okay I will be buffering the
number one the operant and also the
number two okay so all these will be
stored in these different buffers so
that's our first step okay so we are
going to name this buffer
values now uh in the Second Step as I
said we need to use some kind of
condition because the operant is
changing and depending on the operant uh
we need to perform the mathematical
operation accordingly right so we are
going to use the F statement here okay
so I'm going to use the F statement here
and in the condition uh then uh we need
to check what kind of operant it is
right so for that we'll be using another
test step and that is called tbox
evaluation tool
okay so here we can put some expression
which can be verified okay so that will
be our condition so in this uh eval uh
we will be putting an expression to
check what is the operant okay so I'll
be checking here B of
operant okay and uh I'll be putting this
in
codes so whenever you are using the tbox
evalution tool and you are um working
with different types of Expressions you
should always use single codes uh so
that uh everything is escaped properly
okay and then equal
uh we'll be
using um the first plus sign so for
addition
okay so it will check whether this
operand is plus uh and if it is then um
we will be again adding the same module
here
okay and then in the then statement in
the result section we'll be using
something called the math expression so
it is used to perform any mathematical
calculations so inside this uh we'll be
then adding the buffers okay so num
one and then uh we'll be adding num two
here and then we'll be closing this okay
so this is the math expression where it
will perform the mathematical operation
okay so this is for addition similarly
we need to make four different if
statements okay for four different
operations so I will be uh pasting this
four times
okay and then here we'll be changing the
conditions okay so we will have one
for
subtraction and we'll change uh the
operation
here and then we'll have for
multiplication and the final one would
be for a modular operation okay so we
will put the operation here and then
we'll go to the last
one and we will add the mod symbol here
okay so the
mod
and and the then we will do
that okay so these are all the four
different operations which uh we need to
perform okay and everything is inside uh
if else statement although it is not
super efficient uh we have doing this
but there is no other way of doing this
particular uh problem right so we need
to use the if then else
statements so now we are going to mark
this as completed that's all what we
need to do and now let's go ahead and
run this couple of times so that we can
see it is working for all the different
operations okay so I'm going to run
this okay so as you can see uh
the result was populated with the
correct value and the automation
obstacle was completed right now you can
see um now this particular sign has
changed okay so it is a subtraction now
so what we'll do uh we will go ahead and
run this once
more okay so as you can see both of the
times uh everything was changing but
still uh the automation was able to
handle all those changes
um and effectively this is um automating
the calculator itself right because we
have been performing all the
calculations which are part of the
calculator so uh this is how you can
perform different mathematical
operations using the math function and
then using the if else statements you
can put conditions uh and you can check
for different conditions and based on
whatever condition it is you can perform
the respective
operation that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next video